Joseph Christian

Business Information System Graduate | Full-Stack Developer

Balikpapan, Indonesia | +62895361700188 | josephjcwork@gmail.com, LinkedIn, Github

SUMMARY

I am a Developer specializing in creating web applications with an optimal user experience. Committed to delivering efficient, scalable, and accessible solutions, I focus on achieving business goals while enhancing user satisfaction. With an analytical mindset and keen attention to detail, I strive to deliver tangible value in every project I work on.

EXPERIENCE

Petra Christian University

Surabaya

Full Stack Developer (Freelance)

February, 2024 – June, 2024

- Developed a website using Laravel to streamline helpdesk services for the ELTC unit at Petra Christian University.
- Conducted requirements analysis, designed databases, and implemented ticketing system features for related services.
- Collaborated with the PPSI and ELTC units at Petra Christian University to ensure successful testing and implementation of the system.

PT Cross Network Indonesia

Surabaya

Front-End Web Developer Internship

July, 2023 – December, 2023

- Implemented intuitive UI designs for websites using Tailwind CSS, ensuring responsive and user-friendly interfaces.
- Develop functional websites with HTML and Javascript in collaboration with fellow programmers to provide a seamless user experience.

PROJECT

Personal Website November, 2024

This platform highlights my skills and my projects. Built with React and TypeScript, the website utilizes Tailwind CSS to deliver a seamless and responsive user experience.

Public Forum Discussion

October, 2024

This project is a simple public forum where users can join discussions and explore threads. It was built with React, Redux, and other tools in the React ecosystem, with a few unit tests implemented to ensure basic functionality.

Helpdesk for Services at ELTC Unit of Petra Christian University

February, 2024 – June, 2024

This platform is designed to facilitate the management of complaints, classroom bookings, and other services for the Excellence in Learning and Teaching Center unit at Petra Christian University. Each service operates through a ticketing system, ensuring more structured and efficient management, and it's developed with Laravel, PHP, and JavaScript, blending Bootstrap and CSS to create a seamless and dynamic user experience.

EDUCATION

Petra Christian University

Surabaya

Business Information System, GPA: 3.62/4.00

August, 2020 – July, 2024

• Thesis: Helpdesk Information System for Services At Excellence in Learning and Teaching Center To Increase User Satisfaction

CORE SKILL

- **Programing Language:** Javascript, React, Typescript, PHP, Python
- Framework: Laravel
- **Database:** PostgreSQL & MySQL
- Soft Skill: Teamwork, Problem Solving, Adaptability

CERTIFICATION

- Learn to Create a Website with React by Dicoding
- Learn Web Application Fundamentals with React by <u>Dicoding</u>
 Become a React Web Developer Expert by <u>Dicoding</u>